Career Summary

Ivan has experience developing object-oriented applications for a period of eight years, so web applications, back-end applications and web services SOAP and REST. He is a team player and he always approaches his work by analyzing everything around him. He has experience in different databases such as SQL, MySql, Oracle and MongoDB. He developed projects as a full-stack developer. He has worked with methodologies such as SCRUM and Traditional. He is a responsible person, punctual and has an optimal performance working in a group.

Summary of Qualifications

Frameworks:

Microsoft .Net Framework (C#)
Spring Boot, Data, Security
Maven /Gradle
Angular JS
React
Open API (Swagger UI)
Spock/Groovy (Testing)
JSF

Cloud Providers:

AWS (i.e. EC2, RDS, S3, etc.) Azure

Platforms:

Linux Docker

Front-end:

CSS3 HTML5

Application Servers:

Tomcat Glassfish Websphere Weblogic 11

Databases:

MySQL SQL Oracle 11g MongoDB (NoSQL) Redis **Tools:**

Datapower Volante Designer

CI/CD:

Jenkins /sonar

Source Control:

GIT TFS SVN

Soft-skills:

Customer orientation
Creativity and Javascript
Goal orientation
Problem solving
Autonomy

Career History

Scotiabank - Global GBS, Bogotá Colombia

Software Engineer Lead

Oct. 2019- Oct 2022

- Development of micro services based on development standards stipulated by the bank on the Java 8 programming language, with a Database manager SQL and Redis.
- Consumption of REST services under the REACT library, with management of Redux and nginex.
- Consumption of SOAP services from the Banking Core in order to create microservices for the project
- Development of functionalities for the bank's CRM on the language of JAVA 8 programming. Additionally, participation on the migration of the same platform
- Implementation of Azure as a Services
- Design of services under the YAML services.

The previous micro services were developed under the Spring Boot framework, together with Bitbucket, Gradle, Jenkins, Sql Server DB Manager, Sonar, BlackDuck, fortify. Likewise, I work on the Agile methodology.

BBVA, Bogotá, Colombia

Java Developer - Software Engineer

Dec. 2017 - Sept. 2019

- Designed the RAML Web services-based language YAML.
- Consumption of REST and SOAP services through external entities, in order to expose REST services in the bank for the consumption of different channels in it, under the Java language, such as:
 - o SOI ACH: REST Web service which describes the economic Activity of the person.
 - o Informa Colombia: SOAP Web service which describes the current situation of a Company.
 - o Aportes En Línea: SOAP service which describes the economic Activity of the person.
 - o DECEVAL: SOAP Web service which allows create and sign a promissory Note of a person.
 - o Certicamara: SOAP services which allow to validate a footprint against the Database of the National Registry of Colombia and signature of digital documents.
- Test automation using Git, Jenkins / SONAR.
- Developed a Web service in a proxy Data Power.
- Defined projects estimate.

MEGALINEA (Bogota's Bank), Bogotá, Colombia

Analyst developer

Development of the Java language based on the needs of Banco De Bogotá.

Activities:

- Development web Application with framework Spring and Angular with Weblogic Application Server and SQL DataBase with SVN version driver.
- Data mapping using the Volante Designer tool
- Create and execute queries to solve pre-existent issues on delivered projects.
- Implemented agile methodologies for products developments

Autentic, Bogotá, Colombia

Oct. 2016 - March. 2017

Software Engineer II

Development and implementation of web applications under the REST and SOAP architecture.

Activities:

- Development web Application in Spring and HTML5 with Tomcat Application Server and MYSOL DataBase with GIT version driver.
- Developed REST web services for Certicamara.

Deloitte, Bogotá, Colombia

Aug. 2015 - Oct. 2016

ERS Assistant

Development of Internal Audit in companies of the financial sector and the Real Sector.

Activities:

- Development of vulnerability testing of web pages and servers of different companies.
- Revision of General Controls of Technology and Management of Different Frameworks (Cobit4.1).

Masivo Capital

Aug. 2014 – Feb. 2015

Software Engineer II

Development and implementation of web applications under an Intranet of the company.

Activities:

- Developed different applications within Intranet of the company based in .
- Documentation of user's manual of the different applications as requirements needed.
- Create and execute queries to solve pre-existent issues on delivered projects.

March 2017 - Dec.2017

Education

Pontificia Universidad Javeriana, Bogotá Colombia Business Software Architecture specialization July. 2019 - June 2020

Universidad El Bosque, Bogotá, Colombia BS, Systems Engineering. (Computer Science)

Feb. 2010 - Feb. 2016

Languages

- Spanish (native speaker)
- English (Intermediate)